# Samuel Ruiz

Website: SamLuvs.Pizza Delhi, CA, 95315 (209) 809-9422 samuelruizdev@gmail.com

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

Adaptable Computer Science major currently attending California State University Stanislaus, with 7+ years of work experience. Aiming to leverage a proven knowledge of software engineering, web development, and communication skills to successfully fill a React.js developer position. Frequently praised as hard-working by my peers, I can be relied upon to help your company achieve its goals.

## **EDUCATION**

### CALIFORNIA STATE UNIVERSITY STANISLAUS

Turlock, CA

B.S. Computer Science Candidate (Expected graduation Fall 2020)

- Award And Honor: Best Mobile App (Snap Shop) HACKMerced Hackathon, Best use of Snap Kit (Green Gene) HACKMerced Hackathon, Best Domain Name (Turlock Pot Holes) StanHACKS Hackathon, Student Leadership Awards Nominee for Computer Science Club
- Extracurricular Activity: Computer Science Club Treasurer & Board Member (Nov 2018- Nov 2020)

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Google Developer Group Cloud Turlock

Turlock, CA

Organizer

Jan 2018 – Nov 2020

- Build relationships with sponsors and co-organizers to plan scope and format of events, to establish and monitor budgets, or to review administrative procedures and event progress.
- Conduct technical workshops where students learn cutting edge computer science topics and technologies that aren't taught in our campus's classes.
- Build a welcoming community of Computer Science Students by organizing team building events.

Novo Technologies Modesto, CA

Front-End Developer & UI/UX Intern

Nov 2019 – Feb 2020

- Worked with industry standards and popular front-end frameworks including React, Node.JS, C#, Machine Learning, Vision Recognition, and several others to build products for clients on strict time requirements.
- Worked under a UI/UX industry professional to design and create the UI/UX for our React.JS Projects so we were in charge of UI/UX and programming.

T-Mobile Wireless

Turlock, CA

*Mobile Expert / Sales* 

Jan 2018 – Jan 2019

- Became part of an invested team that helped our store become the #1 leading store in the district in terms of sales and customer satisfaction.
- Prioritized customer's needs by familiarizing them with all the options our company had to offer and demonstrated a ~90% customer satisfaction score, months after being hired up through my departure.
- Trained to communicate with customers effectively in order to make every transaction, a personal, and unique experience. This effectively led to easily achieving my monthly quotas.

Cloth 5 Inc.

Melbourne (Remote), Victoria

Lead Graphic Designer / Graphic Artist

Aug 2012 – Feb 2014

- Demonstrated my graphic design skills by utilizing the vast Adobe Suite Software, including: Photoshop, Illustrator, Lightroom, & Dreamweaver in order to ensure graphics were created on a strict deadline basis.
- Achieved the status of Lead Graphic Designer within 3 months of obtaining the position of Graphic Designer Intern.
- Communicated and collaborated with co-workers remotely, across the world in order to discuss the nature of articles and graphics that were needed to be created to best compliment our writer's articles.

### ADDITIONAL SKILLS

• Spanish Speaker - Conversational, Reading, & Writing

## **CREDENTIALS AND LICENSES**

• California Basic Education Skills Test (Substitute Teaching)

### REFERENCES

References available upon request